<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Jonathan Godt</origin><origin>Rex Baum</origin><origin>Eric Jones</origin><pubdate>20180824</pubdate><title>Factor of Safety for Hawaii Islands</title><geoform>Vector Digital Data Set (Polygon)</geoform></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>
    Preliminary  map showing landslide susceptibility for Hawaii

    The map data depict areas of steep slopes where landslides may begin. The map data do not depict the where material from landslides or debris flows will travel and deposit. The map data are classified into susceptibility categories of "very-high", "high", and "moderate". The categories indicate the relative potential for landslide initiation and are based on expert judgement and a simple slope-stability model applied to digital topography following the methods of Harp and others (2009). The digital topography has a resolution of 10 m or 33 ft. Included in the map data are a vector data set of stream channels from the National Hydrography Dataset (https://nhd.usgs.gov/). These "watch streams" indicate some of the possible paths debris flows, other landslides, or flash flooding may travel. Landslides and flows of water and debris may extend laterally beyond the watch streams as they travel and encounter roads, culverts, and other infrastructure not depicted in the digital topography.  The susceptibility and watch stream map data have not been tested or calibrated to past events.  This information is preliminary or provisional and is subject to revision. It is being provided to meet the need for timely best science. The information is provided on the condition that neither the USGS nor the U.S. Government shall be held liable for any damages resulting from the authorized or unauthorized use of the information.
   </abstract><purpose>In response to hurricane Lane, we have identified areas of higher landslide susceptibility.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20180824</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>observed</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>None planned</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-160.22239125</westbc><eastbc>-154.742608276</eastbc><northbc>22.23285921</northbc><southbc>18.897663671</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>USGS information products</themekt><themekey>USGS information products</themekey></theme></keywords><accconst>None. Please see 'Distribution Info' for details.</accconst><useconst>None. Users are advised to read the data set's metadata thoroughly to understand appropriate use and data limitations.</useconst><native>Environment as of Metadata Creation: Microsoft [Unknown] Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5 (Build 6491) Service Pack N/A (Build N/A)</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>No formal attribute accuracy tests were conducted.</attraccr></attracc><logic>No formal logical accuracy tests were conducted.</logic><complete>Data set is considered complete for the information presented, as described in the abstract. Users are advised to read the rest of the metadata record carefully for additional details.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>A formal accuracy assessment of the horizontal positional information in the data set has not been conducted.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>A formal accuracy assessment of the vertical positional information in the data set has either not been conducted, or is not applicable.</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>
     Use the Factor of Safety model to create files

     Reference cited:
     Harp, E.L., Reid, M.E., McKenna, J.P., Michael, J.A., 2009, Mapping of hazard from rainfall-triggered landslides in developing countries: Examples from Honduras and Micronesia, Engineering Geology, v. 104, no. 3–4, p. 295-311, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enggeo.2008.11.010.
    </procdesc><procdate>20180824</procdate></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>3</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>4</utmzone><transmer><sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer><longcm>-159.0</longcm><latprjo>0.0</latprjo><feast>500000.0</feast><fnorth>0.0</fnorth></transmer></utm></gridsys><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.6096</absres><ordres>0.6096</ordres></coordrep><plandu>Meter</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D_North_American_1983</horizdn><ellips>GRS_1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222101</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed Name="FOS_All_HI_Islandsdiss1"><enttyp><enttypl>Attribute Table</enttypl><enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd><enttypds>Producer defined</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>gridcode</attrlabl><attrdef>Unknown</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>1</rdommin><rdommax>3</rdommax></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>LS_sus</attrlabl><attrdef>landslide susceptibility</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>High</edomv><edomvd>classes of landslide susceptibility</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>Moderate</edomv><edomvd>Unknown</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>Very High</edomv><edomvd>Unknown</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>The entity and attribute information provided here describes the tabular data associated with the data set. Please review the detailed descriptions that are provided (the individual attribute descriptions) for information on the values that appear as fields/table entries of the data set.</eaover><eadetcit>The entity and attribute information was generated by the individual and/or agency identified as the originator of the data set. Please review the rest of the metadata record for additional details and information.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey - ScienceBase</cntorg></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailing</addrtype><address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302”</address><city>Denver</city><state>Colorado</state><postal>80225</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>Distributor assumes no liability for misuse of data.</distliab><custom>This should make it's way to the National Map, but for now it's only available through the contacts.</custom></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20180824</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>GHSC Data Steward</cntper><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Geologic Hazards Science Center</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Open Data Policy coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype><address>1711 Illinois St.</address><city>Golden</city><state>Colorado</state><postal>80401</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-273-8500</cntvoice><cntemail>ghsc_metadata@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv></metainfo></metadata>